Guide to the New York State College of Agriculture Administration records, 1896-2002.
New York State College of Agriculture Administration records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Agriculture Administration records, 1896-2002.
21-1-1840
New York State College of Agriculture.
5.3 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Faculty personnel forms and work sheets of statistics drawn from the forms.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Faculty personnel forms (1927-1928) listing name, salary, educational background, previous teaching experience, previous experience at Cornell University, courses taught, hours per week for each course, and number of graduate and undergraduate students in each course; also, work sheets of statistics drawn from the forms.
Includes committee meeting minutes, including faculty meetings (1896-1978) and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture.; New York State College of Agriculture--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture--Curricula.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Faculty.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences--Curricula.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Faculty Personnel Forms
Series II. Committees
Series III. Reports
Series IV. Legislation and Bylaws
Series V. Faculty Meeting Minutes
Series VI. Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Faculty Personnel Forms
  - Ag. Ec. and Farm Management, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Agronomy, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Animal Husbandry, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Botany, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dairy Industry, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Entomology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Forestry, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meteorology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Plant Breeding, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Plant Pathology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Pomology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Poultry Husbandry, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Rural Education, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Rural Engineering, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Rural Social Organization, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Vegetable Gardening, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Zoology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Extension Teaching, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Farm Practice, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Omit," "Taught no courses," "Cafeteria," "Nursery School", 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Worksheets, Number of Student Hours, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Worksheets, Number of class hours per week, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Worksheets, Percentages of Time, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Home Economics - Extension, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Home Economics - Family Life, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Home Economics - Foods and Nutrition, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Home Economics - Household Art, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Home Economics - Instituion Management, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Home Economics - Textiles and Clothing, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Anatomy, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Material Medical and Small Animal Clinic, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Medicine, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "No Instruction", 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Pathology and Bacteriology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Physiology, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Surgery, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Series II. Committees
  - Policy Committee Documents, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Policy Committee Agendas, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Policy Committee Agendas and Memos, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Policy Committee, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Policy Committee Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Policy Committee Meetings, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Policy Committee Meetings (1), 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Policy Committee Meetings (2), 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Policy Committee (including discussion of Affirmative Action in hiring) (1), 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Policy Committee (including discussion of Affirmative Action in hiring) (2), 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Policy Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Committee on Structure and Faculty Governance, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Math Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Economic Status Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Admissions Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - SUNY Faculty Senate Committee, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Oral and Written Expression Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Grade Inflation, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Nominations Committee, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Nominations Committee, 1978-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Elections for Standing Committees, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Academic Achievement and Petitions Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Scholarship in Teaching Committee, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Committee on the Economic and Professional Status of the Faculty, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Admissions Committee, 1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Academic Integrity Board, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - College Fund; Grants and Awards, 1973-1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Scholarship and Financial Aid Recipients, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1979-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scholarship Committee, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Undergraduate Affairs Subcommittee, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Planning Councils--Program Reviews and Characterizations, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CALS Strategic Positioning, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Committee Volunteers, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Committee Volunteers, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Standing Committee Elections, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Standing Committee Material, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Standing Committee Member Rosters, 1940-1975 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - University Appeals Panel, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - College Curriculum Committee (1), 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - College Curriculum Committee (2), 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Committee on Economic Status, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - New York State Assembly and Senate Intern Program, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mann Library Committee, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Study Abroad Committee, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - "Principles of Affiliation" Agreement with SUNY Ag/Tech Colleges, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Photos at Signing of "Principles of Affiliation" Agreement, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Series III. Reports
  - Budget Report for the College, Fiscal Year beginning October 1, 1915 (Box 7)
  - The Improvement of College Teaching Report by J. D. Novak (1), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Improvement of College Teaching Report by J. D. Novak (2), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Committee on Scholarship in Teaching, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pink Covered Reports, concerning CALS Students (for example, grade distribution, admissions, student life, occupational status, etc. Guide to reports in this folder) (1), 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pink Covered Reports (2), 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Pink Covered Reports (3), 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Pink Covered Reports (4), 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Pink Covered Reports (5), 1940s-1970s (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Facts and Statistics about CALS compiled by Royse Murphy, 1998 (Box 7)
- Series IV. Legislation and Bylaws
  - Organization Charts of CALS, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Legislation of the Faculty of CALS, 1930s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Legislation of the Faculty of CALS, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Legislation of the Faculty of CALS, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legislation of the Faculty of CALS, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Legislation of the Faculty of CALS, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Annual Financial Report, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University Charter and Bylaws, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Series V. Faculty Meeting Minutes
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. I, 1896-1908 (Box 4)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. II, 1908-1912 (Box 4)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. III, 1912-1916 (Box 4)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. IV, 1916-1919 (Box 4)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. V, 1919-1923 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. VI, 1923-1927 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. VII, 1927-1930 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. VIII, 1930-1935 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. IX, 1935-1940 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. X, 1940-1944 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XI, 1944-1948 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XII, 1948-1951 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XIII, 1951-1954 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XIV, 1954-1957 (Box 5)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XV, 1957-1959 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XVI, 1959-1961 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XVII, 1961-1963 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XVIII, 1963-1965 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XIX, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XX, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XXI, 1969-1971 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XXII, 1971-1973 (Box 6)
  - Bound Faculty Meeting Minutes Vol. XXIII, 1973-1975 (Box 6)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 6)
  - Faculty Meeting Minutes, December and May 1983; March-April 1984 (Box 7)
- Series VI. Memorabilia
  - Agricultural Banquet Program-5th Annual, 1905 (Box 7)